Greta Ru-Mei Zu

Personal website: https://github.com/zu-greta

PROJECTS

Artificial Intelligence course final project

 Develop an agent that can win against another player in a game of Colosseum Survival. Using techniques such as Monte Carlo Tree Search, A* Search and heuristics to efficiently make decisions and win against any opponent.

Web Development course project

- Full-stack web dev project (XAMPP, HTML/CSS/Javascript/PHP/SQLite3) creating a booking tool for school staff and students.
- https://www.cs.mcgill.ca/~gzu/socs_sisters/landing

McWics Hackathon project - BCV

 Develop a full-stack web-app (React, Drizzle, postgresql) that stores user information (job experiences, projects, skills...) and with the input of a job description, generates a CV with information most relevant to the job description with the help of a Gemini API call.

Codejam14 Hackathon project - MealMates

Develop a full-stack mobile app (React-Native, Django-rest, SQLite) that
allows users to swipe through food images from restaurants near them and
curate a list of interested restaurants as well as match with friends on similar
restaurants to try out together.

Database Systems course final project

 Design an application for a travelling agency, where users can book flights, hotels or rent cars. Created relational schemas, E/R diagrams, SQL queries and JDBC (Java) to provide a database and functions to navigate and use it.

Compiler Design project (in progress)

Design and create a compiler for Mini-C (a subset of the C) using Java.

Operating Systems course project

• Using C programming language, create an operating system simulation including a shell, memory management and filesystem management.

Calendar/Reminder app personal project (in progress)

Develop an iOs Calendar and ToDo list application using SwuitUI and XCode.
 The goal is to compare functionalities between iOs and macOs, using a database, and looking at possibilities of syncing between devices.

RESEARCH PROJECT

TikTok algorithm analysis - team project under supervision of Professor Vybihal

 Overcoming web scraping data barriers from TikTok using bots and bypassing biases from the algorithm. Analyzing the data to see the different treatment towards user gender, food negative/positive contents and the biases that come with that.

WORK EXPERIENCE

- Notetaker for data science course at McGill University. [January 2024-Ongoing]
- Corrector for physics labs at Marianopolis College. [August 2022-June 2023]

Contact me:

(438) 926-6499

Gretarm.zu@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/greta-ru-mei-zu/

EDUCATION

McGill University, Montreal QC

Bachelor of Science Computer Science (August 2022-Ongoing) GPA: 3.8 out of 4.0

Marianopolis College, Montreal QC

DCS in Honours Health Science (August 2020-June 2022) R-Score: 37.825

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages:

- Java, C, Python, C++, Bash, MIPS, OCaml, SQL, Swift, Javascript, React
- HTML, CSS (Markup languages)

Relevant Courses:

- Algorithm and Data Structures
- Artificial Intelligence
- Programming Languages and Paradigms
- Intro to Software Systems
- Intro to Computer Systems
- Software Design
- Operating Systems
- Algorithm Design
- Database Systems
- Intro to Data Science
- Principles of Web Development
- Distributed Systems
- Machine Learning
- Compiler Design

SKILLS & QUALIFICATIONS

- Fluent in English and French
- Can work well in teams and independently
- Excellent organization and time-management skills
- Strong communication skills
- Quick learner and willing to learn and put in effort

LANGUAGES

- English (Fluent)
- French (Fluent)